# Evgenia Melnikova

evkmelnikov.a@gmail.com | GitHub | 654-959-501 | Barcelona, Spain

# **ABOUT**

Hi! I'm Evgenia, an International Business Analyst/PM. I've been living in Barcelona for the last 7 years and over the last year and a half I've dedicated over 8 hours daily to the craft of software engineering.

Opting for mentorship over traditional bootcamps, I chose to learn under a Sr. Director of Engineering at AttackIQ, who brings over 20 years of industry expertise. Thanks to this approach, I learned not only to develop software but also to troubleshoot issues effectively and ask informed questions, ensuring robust solutions and continuous learning in future roles.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: Python (Intermediate), JavaScript (Basic), C (Basic)

Frameworks: Django, Django Rest Framework, React.js

Technologies: Git, Docker, Docker Compose, CI/CD via GitHub Actions, AWS EC2.

Python Libraries: Slack/Twilio packages, BeautifulSoup, requests, unittest/pytest, PyPDF2, etc.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

vritat, Barcelona   Junior Software Developer (Freelance)	Jan 2024 — Aug 2024
HP Inc., Barcelona   Business Analyst/PM	Aug 2021 — Present
Relocation to Barcelona, Spain	Nov 2017
Baker & McKenzie, Moscow   Management Accountant / Reporting Analyst	Nov 2015 — Nov 2017
EY, Moscow   Project Coordinator / Executive Assistant	Nov 2012 — Jun 2015

### **PROJECTS**

- News Management Portal: A platform developed for the *vritat.com* news portal to streamline the process
  of curating positive news. It fetches news from various sources, performs sentiment analysis, and filters out
  negative news, ensuring only positive stories are posted. Built using Django Rest Framework for the
  backend and React.js for the frontend, the project utilizes Docker Compose for containerization and is
  deployed on AWS EC2 with continuous integration and deployment managed by GitHub Actions. (GitHub)
- AccuWeather Insights: Built a stay up-to-date application for weather forecasts. The project allows for customized notifications, providing comprehensive and timely weather updates. It leverages the AccuWeather API, BeautifulSoup for web scraping, and Slack or Twilio for notifications. (GitHub)
- Meneame.net News Email Delivery: An application that parsed political news from meneame.net and sent an email with the daily fresh news. The app was executed every day via a cron job in AWS EC2 (<u>GitHub</u>).
- Job Search App: Developed a job search/posting application using React.js. (GitHub)
- eCommerce App: Developed an eCommerce application using React.js. (GitHub)
- **Blog Web App**: Built as the final project for the Udacity Web Development course, guided by Reddit's creator. It uses Google App Engine and webapp2, with a transition to SQLAlchemy for database support. The project showcases user authentication, blog posting, and viewing features. Built with Python, webapp2, and Jinja templating. (GitHub)
- Other small projects such as *all* the **Automating Boring Stuff with Python** book projects. (e.g. <u>GitHub</u>)

#### **COURSES**

Complete React Developer in 2024 (w/ Redux, Hooks, GraphQL): Zero to Mastery, ZTM Academy

Next-Level Python: Become a Python Expert, ArjanCodes Services B.V.

Django Bootcamp: Zero to Mastery, ZTM Academy

Linux Command Line Basics, Udacity

Currently starting my training on platforms such as LeetCode, Codewars and Exercism.

#### MENTOR

### **SOFTWARE ENGINEERING BOOKS**

These are some of the software engineering books I went through during my learning journey.

# The Missing README: A Guide for the New Software Engineer

This book allowed me to understand a little bit better how software engineering organizations work on a day-to-day basis.

# Automating Boring Stuff with Python, 2nd Edition, No Starch Press, Al Sweigart, ~500 pages

This book made me understand the wide range of things one can easily build with a programming language like Python. I implemented all the projects.

# C Programming - A Modern Approach, 2nd Edition, KN King, ~830 pages

This book allowed me to have a low level perspective on how variables, pointers, compilation, etc work before I jumped to more high level languages like Python or Javascript. I implemented all exercises up to chapter 9 (~220 pages) and read through to chapter 20 (~500 pages).

### **EDUCATION**

# **Moscow University for the Humanities, Moscow**

Bachelor's Degree in Finance / Accounting, Analysis and Audit

#### **LANGUAGES**

English, Spanish, Russian